# Ryan Skeans

(951) 234-1872 | ryanskeans@gmail.com | San Diego, CA

## **Summary**

Software Engineer with experience in Typescript, CSS, Web Components, and React. Proven success developing and deploying software solutions. Experienced in agile methodologies, code refactoring, bug fixing, and code development. I am excited to continue expanding and enhancing my skillset as part of an excellent team.

### **Experience**

# SS&C Advent | San Francisco, CA Software Engineer | 02/2022 - Present

- Integrated both REST and GraphQL API's into our investment management application to enable seamless tracking and rebalancing of client assets.
- Utilized a modern tech stack including Sass, React, Web Components, Typescript, Cypress, and Express.
- Wrote tests and collaborated with QA/QE teams to ensure a high quality user experience at all times.
- Developed a wide range of React components ranging from buttons and dropdowns to new screens.
- Leveraged a Javascript data visualization framework to create dynamic, data driven SVG charts.
- Collaborated with backend developers to implement front-end functionalities for complex web applications, ensuring seamless integration of UI components with backend services.
- Contributed to the company-wide design system that demanded components be powerful, but also highly reusable.
- Optimized website performance by regularly refactoring to newer web technologies and trimming down on bloat.
- Utilized tools like Jenkins, Github Actions, and Docker images to get work done efficiently and quickly.

# Prudential Financial | San Francisco, CA Senior Product Management Associate | 07/2020 - 02/2022

- Worked to build and enhance Prudential's retail/direct to consumer money management products.
- Analyzed and provided insights on KPI's using Tableau and Adobe Analytics.
- Participated in design sprints aimed at providing the customer with the best experience possible.
- Helped unblock and guide user stories to completion in an agile workplace.

# Prudential Financial | Sunnyvale, CA Product Management Intern | 06/2019 - 08/2019

- Worked collaboratively with UX, UI, and backend engineers to develop intuitive workflows based on competitive research.
- Helped review, summarize, and distribute results from multiple rounds of user testing for our product.
- Created low fidelity wire frames and coordinated with UX teams to refine based on industry best practices.

#### Education

California Polytechnic State University | San Luis Obispo, CA B.S. Business Administration, Financial Management | 06/2020

#### Top Skills

React, Web Components, Typescript, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Sass, REST API's, GraphQL, Cypress, Web Services, SQL, Node.js, Express.js, Webpack, Material, D3.js, Git, GitHub, NPM, Python

#### Websites

Github: https://github.com/skeanster

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ryanskeans/

Personal Website: https://skeanster.github.io/